(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.1",
"generated_at": "2026-06-19T00:30:22.496395",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
天音かなた 卒業LIVE 『絶対的』
[Title: Amane Kanata Graduation LIVE — 'The Absolute']
天音かなた 2025.12.27
Amane Kanata 2025.12.27
ようこそ ★天音かなたの3Dへ★
[Text: Welcome to Amane Kanata's 3D Debut! ]
はい、サイドチェストー！
Yes, side chest!
誰でも分かります！
Anyone can tell!
出会えた
That we met...
奇跡に
...was a miracle.
もう息が止まりそうだよ
It almost takes my breath away.
荒野のピース
[Song: Piece of the Wilderness]
何を見ているの？
What are you looking at?
どこまでも澄んだ瞳で
With those endlessly clear eyes?
二人だけなら伝わる
If it's just the two of us, we can understand.
世界できっと すべてが今 始まるから
Because surely, everything in the world is starting now.
君に逢うために
Just to meet you,
生まれてきたと伝えたいんだ決めたんだ
I want to tell you that I was born.
そよ風も 胸刺す
Even the gentle breeze, even the chest-piercing...
視線も全部
...gaze, all of it,
ひりひりする声になるのさ ずっと
will forever turn into a tingling voice.
君のそばにいる
I will be by your side.
濁りのない透き通る気持ちは
These clear, unclouded feelings...
引き裂くものなんてない
...there is nothing that can tear them apart.
二人きり未来さえ飛べるんだ
Just the two of us can even fly to the future.
Ooh... la la la...
どこへ行くの？ 小さな
Where are you going? Even though my small...
自分に今 涙
...self is overflowing with tears right now,
溢れるけど 走り出せる
I can still start running.
もしも はぐれたら
If we ever get separated,
体ごと消してみせる
I will make my entire body vanish.
羽ばたいた 一枚の
Fluttering away,
姿になって
taking the form of a single feather,
君の愛を求めて旅するよ ずっと
I will travel forever, seeking your love.
君を抱きしめる
I will hold you close.
汚れない透き通る気持ちが
These pure, transparent feelings
時を超えて呼び合う
will call out to each other across time.
二人きり未来へと 飛び立つんだ
Just the two of us, taking flight toward the future.
出会えた 奇跡に
To the miracle of our meeting,
もう息が止まりそうだよ
it almost takes my breath away.
繋いだ その手に
In your hand that I hold,
少し強くなれる気がする
I feel like I can become a little stronger.
出会えた 奇跡に
To the miracle of our meeting,
もう息が止まりそうだよ
it almost takes my breath away.
明日も 未来も
Tomorrow, and the future too,
ただどうしようもなく好きだよ
I just love you, helplessly so.
Oh oh oh oh oh...
いつか僕らの上をスレスレに
Once, just grazing above us...
通り過ぎていったあの飛行機を
...that airplane went flying past.
不思議なくらいに憶えてる
I remember it to a strange degree,
意味もないのに何故か
for some reason, even though there's no meaning to it.
不甲斐なくて泣いた日の夜に
On the night of the day I cried from frustration,
ただ強くなりたいと願ってた
I just wished to become stronger.
そのために必要な勇気を
The courage needed for that...
探し求めていた
...is what I was searching for.
残酷な運命が定まっているとして
Even if a cruel fate is already decided,
それがいつの日か僕の前に現れるとして
and even if it appears before me someday,
ただ一瞬 この一瞬
if just for a moment, this single moment...
息ができるなら
...I can draw a breath,
どうでもいいと思えた
then I felt like nothing else mattered.
その心を
That heart of mine...
もう一度
Once more,
遠くへ行け 遠くへ行けと
"Go further! Go further!"
僕の中で誰かが歌う
Someone inside of me is singing,
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
so passionately that I can't help it.
目を腫らした君が二度と悲しまないように笑える
So that you, with your swollen eyes, can laugh and never be sad again,
そんなヒーローになるための歌
this is a song to become that kind of hero.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
So farewell, raise your peace sign,
転がっていくストーリーを
to the story that rolls on!
守りたいだなんて言えるほど
Enough to say I want to protect you...
君が弱くはないの分かってた
...I knew you weren't weak.
それ以上に僕は弱くてさ
Even more than that, I was weak,
君が大事だったんだ
and you were so important to me.
独りで生きていくんだなんてさ
Saying things like "I'm going to live alone,"
口を突いて叫んだあの日から
since that day I blurted it out and screamed.
変わっていく僕を笑いたい
I want to laugh at myself for changing,
一人が怖い僕を
the me who is afraid of being alone.
蹴飛ばして 噛み付いて 息もできなくて
Kicking, biting, unable to even breathe,
騒ぐ頭と腹の奥がぐしゃぐしゃになったって
even if my noisy head and deep inside my stomach became a complete mess.
照らいも 嫌悪も 消えてしまうくらいに
To the point where my affectations and self-loathing completely vanish,
今は触っていたいんだ 君の心に
right now, I want to touch your heart.
僕たちはきっといつか遠く離れた
We will surely, someday, even reach out to...
太陽にすら手が届いて
...the sun so far away,
夜明け前を引っ繰り返して笑おう
turning the pre-dawn upside down and laughing.
そうやって青く燃える色に染まり
Dyeing ourselves in that burning blue color,
おぼつかない足元の向こうへ
beyond our unsteady footsteps,
手をつないで確かに行けるはずだ
holding hands, we can surely go forward.
君と未来を盗み描き出す
Stealing and drawing the future with you,
捻りのないストーリーを
a straightforward story!
瘡蓋だらけ荒れくれた日々が
These rough days covered in scabs,
削り削られ擦り切れた今が
and this present scraped and worn down,
君の言葉で甦る
are revived by your words,
鮮やかにも現れていく
vividly coming to light.
...線を引いても
...even if I drew a line,
どうしても消えなかった
it wouldn't disappear no matter what.
今更なんだから、もう
Since it's too late now...
思い出すな
don't remind me anymore!
間違ってるんだよ
You are wrong!
わかってないよ、あんたら人間も
You don't understand, none of you humans do.
本当も愛も世界も苦しさも
The truth, love, the world, the pain...
人生もどうでもいいよ
even life, I don't care about any of it.
正しいかどうか知りたいのだって防衛本能だ
Even wanting to know if it's right is just a defense instinct.
考えたんだ
I thought about it.
あんたのせいだ
It's all your fault!
考えたってわからないが
Even if I think about it, I don't get it,
本当に年老いたくないんだ
but I really don't want to grow old.
いつか死んだらって思うだけで胸が空っぽになるんだ
Just thinking that I'll die someday makes my chest feel empty.
将来何してるだろうって
Wondering what I'll be doing in the future...
大人になったらわかったよ
Once I grew up, I figured it out.
何もしてないさ
I'm not doing anything at all.
幸せな
Happy...
顔した人が憎いのを
Why do I hate those with happy faces?
どう割り切ったらいいんだ
How can I rationalize this?
満たされない頭の奥の
Deep inside my unsatisfied mind,
化け物みたいな
is a monster-like...
劣等感
...inferiority complex.
誰とか
Who is it? Or what...
間違ってないよね
I'm not wrong, right?
なんだかんだあんたら人間だ
In the end, you all are just human.
愛も救いも優しさも
Love, salvation, and kindness...
根拠がないなんて気味が悪いよ
The lack of basis is just creepy.
ラブソングなんかが痛いのだって防衛本能だ
Even love songs hurting is just a defense instinct.
どうでもいいか
Does it even matter?
あんたのせいだ
It's all your fault!
考えたってわからないし
Even if I think about it, I don't get it,
生きてるだけでも苦しいし
and just living is painful enough.
音楽とかもうわからないし
I don't even understand music anymore.
歌詞とか適当でもいいよ
It's fine if the lyrics are just random.
どうでもいいんだ
I really don't care.
間違ってないだろ
I'm not wrong, am I?
間違ってないよな
I'm not wrong, right?
間違ってるんだよ
It's all wrong!
わかってるんだ
I know that!
あんたら人間も
You humans too.
本当も愛も救いも優しさも人生も
The truth, love, salvation, kindness, life...
どうでもいいんだ
I don't care about any of it.
正しい答えが言えないのだって防衛本能だ
Even being unable to say the right answer is just a defense instinct.
どうでもいいよ
I don't care about it anymore.
あんたのせいだ
It's all your fault!
Ah...
僕だって信念があった
Even I once had beliefs.
今じゃゴミみたいな思い出だ
Now they're just trash-like memories.
何度も君を書いた
I wrote about you over and over again.
売れることこそがどうでもよかったんだ
Selling well was the one thing I didn't care about.
本当だ
It's true.
どちらが正しいのかなんて
Which one of us is right...
誰にもわからないさ
...is something nobody knows.
僕らだけの世界
In a world of our own,
ギブとテイクさ
it's give and take.
補い合えた暁には
When we finally make up for each other's flaws,
同じ夢を見たい
I want us to share the same dream.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて
By calling you cool, I burdened you
ひとりぼっちにさせたのは
and left you all alone,
少し僕のせいなんだよな ごめんね
which is partly my fault... I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But we have to look at reality.
今こそ僕が救けるんだ
Now is the time for me to save you.
抱えないで
Don't carry it all alone,
信じて頼ってほしいんだ
I want you to believe in me and rely on me.
今なんじゃない？
Isn't now the time?
メラメラとたぎる
Raging like a roaring fire,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
there's a sense of justice hiding inside me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
ほら気付けば手を握っている
look, I find myself holding your hand.
ほっとけない
I can't just leave you alone.
そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Where are you going, carrying so much baggage?
ほんのちょっと僕にちょっと預けてみては？
Why don't you try leaving just a little bit of it with me?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero.
はい！皆さん！
Hi, everyone!
とうとう始まってしまいました！
It has finally begun!
天音かなた 卒業ライブ！
The Amane Kanata Graduation Live!
ということでですね、こちら！
And with that, look here!
ハッシュタグが、「#天音かなた卒業ライブ」でございますので
The stream hashtag is "#AmaneKanataGraduationLive"...
ぜひこちらよろしくお願いいたします！
...so please share your thoughts using it!
1曲目に歌った「Mela!」は、実は初配信で歌おうか悩んでいた楽曲だったので
"Mela!", which I sang first, was actually a song I debated singing for my debut stream.
ここで歌えて、すごく良かった！
I'm so glad I got to perform it here!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
小さい頃からね、ヒロインよりヒーローになりたいっていうタイプだったので
Since I was little, I've always wanted to be a hero rather than a heroine...
そういった楽曲をたくさん歌わせていただきました
...so I wanted to sing plenty of songs like that.
ありがとねみんな！拍手もありがとう！
Thank you, everyone! Thanks for the applause, too!
次からはロックで、感情をぶつけていくようなお歌に挑戦しますので...
Next, I'll be taking on rock songs where I pour out all my raw emotions...
ちょっとマイクが... 調整しますので！
Wait, the mic... let me adjust it!
聴いてください！「劣等上等」！
Please listen! "Rettou Joutou" (Bring It On)!
劣等上等 Bring it on
Bring on the inferiority! Bring it on!
列島上々 不眠症
Insomnia is rising across the archipelago!
子供騙しのマセマティカ
Just child's play mathematics,
バレてんだってそんなんじゃプライドがない
I can see right through it, you have no pride like that.
お利口な化粧気取りで
Acting all smart with your makeup,
髪の毛先ばっか弄りてぇ
all you want to do is play with the tips of your hair.
つまんね
How boring.
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Come on, making mistakes is even better!
退屈に手をかけて
Now, put an end to this boredom.
ママ、やっぱダサいわ
Mama, you're uncool after all.
こんなところじゃ終われない
I can't end in a place like this.
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm I feel like going crazy.
ごっこ遊びも 芝居も さようなら
Goodbye to the make-believe and the acting.
ずっとこのままでいられないさ
I can't stay like this forever.
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'm becoming an adult.
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Experiencing both the sweet and sour parts of life now.
パッパッパ 変わる時代
Pa-pa-pa, in this changing era.
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
It's not all bad, right?
過去も罪も罰もすべて
The past, the sins, the punishments, everything...
素手で、愛で、生き抜いて新世紀
...I'll survive with my bare hands, with love, in this new century!
Yeah, 挑発
Yeah, provocation!
あたしたちは no doubt
There's no doubt about us!
緑のアイツにばっか構ってんね
You're always just paying attention to that green guy.
さあ burn up
Come on, burn up!
生ぬるいフューチャー
This lukewarm future...
回答して頂戴な
...please give me an answer.
アップデート入れてどこが駄目なんですか？
What's wrong with installing an update?
さあバグを穿てば やっちゃってコンプライト
So what if we bore into the bugs? Just go and make it light!
あー
Ah...
冗談じゃんブラックジョーク
It's just a joke, a black joke.
中指立てたくなるような事情ありすぎて指が足りねぇからhands up
There are too many situations where I want to flip the bird, not enough fingers so hands up!
and what's up 最低？ もともとだろ bring it on
And what's up? The worst? It was like that from the start, bring it on!
「まあまあ」なんか要らない 欲しがります死ぬまでは
I don't need 'so-so', I'll keep wanting it until I die.
伸びた背丈 育った街に投げキス
Blow a kiss to the city I grew up in, with my grown height.
見せ場はこっから 覚悟しとけよ
The highlight starts here, you'd better be prepared!
ダッダッダ 僕ら大人になる カウンター狙い
Da-da-da, we'll become adults, aiming for a counter-attack.
最低な日々に
In these terrible days...
眈々とかます一撃
A single blow struck firmly.
誰も読めない先まだあいこでしょ
The unreadable future is still a tie, right?
いつも ズレも 避けて 捨てて 生きて 生き抜いて覆すよ
Always, avoiding and discarding deviations, live! Survive and overturn it!
あー
Ah...
くだらないことばっかが譲れない わかるか？ あたしの美学
I can't give up on the trivial things, do you understand? My aesthetic.
この馬鹿正直な拳ひとつが
This one honest fist of mine...
一途なんです 切り札
...is single-minded, my trump card.
愚直なんです がなる劣等
It's simple-minded, roaring inferiority.
一抜けよさらば！
I'm leaving first, goodbye!
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'll become an adult.
Wow... oh...
鋼に打ち込めよ
Drive it into the steel
告国の警笛
The warning siren of the nation
肩越しに響く
Echoing over my shoulder
断末魔
Dying cries
アルカディアの鐘が鳴る日は来るのだろうか
Will the day ever come when the bells of Arcadia ring?
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
イデアの波に蝕まれるな
Don't be swallowed by the wave of ideas
残された空間で僕は
In the space left behind, I...
うかつに肘さえつけやしない
cannot even carelessly rest my elbow
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
アルトとエゴが交差する
Alter and Ego cross paths
XYしか愛せない僕は
I, who can only love X and Y,
Z(なに)を信じて生きれば善い？
what should I believe in to live?
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
世界を敵に回しても
Even if I turn the world against me
表現しきれない
I cannot fully express
衝動に
the impulse
魂が
that my soul
冒される
is being consumed by
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
はい！
Yes!
皆さんありがとうございます！
Thank you, everyone!
ここにね、何があると思います？
What do you think is right here?
水！
Water!
今回は、あの、結構歌に集中するラインナップで来ましたけれども
This time, I've come with a lineup where I focus quite a bit on singing, but...
トレンド1位って本当ですかこれ？
Is it true that we're #1 on trending?
嘘かもしれませんけれども。本当かな？
It might be a lie, but... Is it true?
ガチかも？
Maybe for real?
ありがとう、みんな！
Thank you, everyone!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
かっこいいと言ってくれてるのを見ながら...
As I watch you all say I look cool...
メガホンマイクが手からすっぽ抜けかけましたよ！本当に。
The megaphone mic almost slipped right out of my hand! Seriously.
焦ったわ。
That was scary.
ということでね、えーっと、何かに挑んでいく曲みたいなのが好きなので、元々。
And so, since I've always liked songs where you challenge something...
「劣等上等」と「ぼくらの16bit戦争」を歌わせていただきました！
I sang 'Rettou Joutou' and 'Bokura no 16bit Sensou'!
ね！すごい大好きなかっこいい楽曲たちなので、ぜひぜひ原曲もチェックしてみてください！
Right! They are awesome songs that I love so much, so please do check out the original versions too!
ちょっと待って。僕VTuberなんで着替えは何秒かかると思う？
Wait a sec. I'm a VTuber, so how many seconds do you think it takes to change?
1秒だ！
One second!
ほれ！
Look!
ふふ、すごいでしょ？
Hehe, amazing, right?
これがVTuber、バーチャルアイドルね。
This is what a VTuber, a virtual idol is.
では、このまま続けていくぞ！
Well then, let's keep going just like this!
ローリンガール
[Song: Rolling Girl]
ロンリーガールはいつまでも
The lonely girl is always...
届かない夢見て
...dreaming of unreachable dreams.
騒ぐ頭の中を bruising
With her noisy mind...
掻き回して、
...churned up...
掻き回して。
...and churned up.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、
'No problem,' she mutters,
言葉は失われた？
Were the words lost?
もう失敗、
Another failure,
もう失敗。
Another failure.
間違い探しに終われば、
If it ends as a search for mistakes,
また、回るの！
it'll spin again!
もう一回、
One more time,
もう一回。
One more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
'I will roll again today,' says the girl,
少女は言う
the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
while playing meanings into her words!
「もう良いかい？」
'Are you ready?'
「まだですよ、
'Not yet,'
まだまだ先は見えないので。
'because the end is still not in sight.'
息を止めるの、今。」
'I'll hold my breath... now.'
ローリンガールの成れの果て
The end of the rolling girl...
届かない、向こうの色
...at the unreachable color on the other side.
騒ぐ頭の中を掻き回して、掻き回して。
Stirring, churning the noise inside her head.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
She muttered, 'no problem,'
言葉にしがみついた
and clung to those words.
どうなったって良いんだってさ
They say they don't care what happens,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうとさ
they even say let's make mistakes,
誘う、坂道
on this inviting slope.
もう一回、もう一回。
Once more, once more.
私をどうか転がしてと
'Please roll me again,'
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl said, the girl said,
無口に意味を重ねながら！
playing with the meaning of silent words!
もう一回、もう少し。
Once more, just a little more.
もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと
Thinking she'll see something soon,
息を止めるの、今。
she holds her breath, for now.
もう一回、もう一回。
Once more, once more.
私は今日も転がりますと
'I'll roll again today,'
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl said, the girl said,
言葉に笑みを重ねながら！
playing with the meaning of her smiles!
「もう良いかい？」「もう良いよ。」
'Are you ready?' 'Yes, I am.'
そろそろ君も辛くなったろう、ね。
'You must be getting tired of this too, right?'
息を止めるの、今。
I'll just stop breathing, now.
誰も見てない夢を見せるよ だから
I'll show you a dream that no one has ever seen before, so
僕を信じて
please believe in me.
はい！
Yes!
皆さん、今のは最後のオリジナル楽曲です！
Everyone, that was my last original song!
『誰も見てない夢を見ろ』というね
It's called "Dare mo Mite nai Yume wo Miro"
本日24時にリリース！
and it's releasing today at midnight!
わー！こちらのジャケットをですね
Wow! Please look for this jacket
頼りに探してくださいね、配信を。
to find the stream.
いや、この曲、あまりにも卒業ソングすぎるって思ったでしょ？
You probably thought this song is way too much of a graduation song, right?
これ、実は卒業決める前に作られていた曲で
This was actually made before I decided to graduate.
卒業決める前に…MVは明日ね、あの、明日の20時
The MV will be released tomorrow at 8:00 PM.
もうかなたがいなくなっても、予約投稿というものがある、ネットには。
Even if Kanata is gone, there's scheduled posting on the internet!
ということで、明日の20時に投稿されるんですが
So it will be posted tomorrow at 8:00 PM,
内容も実は卒業を誰も知らずに作っているということで
but the contents were actually made without anyone knowing about the graduation.
なんかこんな偶然の一致でそれっぽくなってしまいました。
So this coincidental match made it look like one.
それを踏まえてまた、なんでやねんと思いながら聞いてください。
With that in mind, please listen to it while thinking "No way!"
ヒゲドライバーさんにね、作詞作曲していただいて
Higedriver wrote and composed the lyrics,
あの『悪魔の子』とかね、いっぱい歌ったりしたんで、超嬉しかったです！
and I sang "Akuma no Ko" and others of his, so I was super happy!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much.
そしてですね、お次はグッズを紹介させていただきます！
And next, let me introduce the merchandise!
こちら！
Here it is!
はい！天音かなた卒業グッズがもう出てます！
Yes! Amane Kanata's graduation merchandise is already out!
なんと出てる！ということで、それでは1つずつ見ていきましょう！
It's actually out! So let's look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First, this one!
はい！アクリルパネルです！可愛いでしょ？じゃん！
Yes! It's the acrylic panel! Cute, right? Ta-da!
こちらね、おしおママに想いをお伝えした上で
This is an illustration drawn by Oshio-mama after I told her my thoughts
書き下ろしていただいたイラストになっております。
specifically for this occasion.
本当にね、あの、みんなに対して、最後は、まあ笑顔かな？とか
Truly, for everyone, at the end, I thought maybe a smile?
青い薔薇というものをね、あの、最初からちょっとモチーフ的に入れたりすることがあったので
And blue roses, which I used as a motif from the beginning,
こちらでまた入れていただきました。可愛いでしょ？
were included here again. Cute, right?
笑顔にしてもらいました。
I had her draw me with a smile.
お次は、こちら！じゃん！
Next, this one! Ta-da!
じゃん！これ、これすごい！かなた＆こなたアクリルスタンドです！
Ta-da! This, this is amazing! Kanata & Konata acrylic stand!
これもね、僕がね、本当にね
This is also, because I really wanted to
こなたという妹というものを、ぜひこの世に残して、生きてえよ！ということで
leave my younger sister Konata in this world, "I want to live!"
僕が欲しいがために生まれたグッズでございます！
So it's a merchandise born just because I wanted it!
可愛いでしょ？エロいよな。
Cute, right? Quite sexy, isn't it?
ということで、次は、こちら！じゃん！
So next, this one! Ta-da!
すっ！ボイスキーホルダーです！
Swoo! It's the voice key holder!
ボイスの6種は、僕がオリジナル考えました。
I came up with the 6 original voices myself.
オリジナル、違う、何でも、ヘイ！こんかなた！とか、だけのさ。じゃん！
Original, no, like "Hey! Kon-kanata!" and such. Ta-da!
で、このイラストもですね、僕が原案を書いて
And for this illustration, I drew the draft
え、プロがすごいよくしてくれましたね。
and the professionals polished it so well.
でも分かるでしょ？かなたその絵柄って。
But you can tell it's Kanata's art style, right?
皆さんありがとうございます。
Thank you, everyone.
収録ボイス届くまでお楽しみに！いっぱいポチポチしてください。
Look forward to the recorded voices! Please click on it a lot!
そして、最後のグッズは、こちら！じゃじゃん！
And the last merchandise is this! Ta-da!
アルティメットへい民認定証！
Ultimate Hey-min Certificate!
これは、最後まで応援してくれた究極のへい民
This is a certificate of the ultimate Hey-min,
アルティメットへい民の認定証です。
the Ultimate Hey-min, who supported me to the end.
シリアルナンバーが入っていて、世界で1枚です。
It has a serial number and is one of a kind in the world.
ちなみに、ちょっと、あの、お買い得、じゃねえや、手が届きやすいので
By the way, it's quite... not "a good deal", but affordable,
これだけでもって、ぜひね、皆さん、あの、思い出によろしくお願いします。
so even just this, everyone, please get it for memories.
今までへい民じゃなかったけど、かなたーん！って思った人もね
Even if you weren't a Hey-min before, but thought "Kanata-n!",
アルティメットへい民だから、あんたは。
you are still an Ultimate Hey-min!
ということでですね、え、お次は、こちら特典ですね。
So next, this is the bonus.
はい、特典はポストカードになっております。
Yes, the bonus is a postcard.
え、数量限定が直筆サイン入りだったんですが、こちらはですね
The limited quantity version with an autographed signature
12月24日の8時から発売開始しており、もう
started selling on December 24th at 8 PM, and it's already...
品切れ…ごめんなさい、完売しているんですけど
sold out, sorry, but
フルセットの方はまだありますので
the full set is still available and comes with
箔押し複製サイン入ってますので、よろしくお願いします。
a hot-stamped copy of the signature, so please check it out.
ちょっとね、このフルセット特典の方は
This full set bonus is like,
寂しいよ！っていう気持ちがちょっと溢れ出た
a bit overflowing with the feeling of "I'm lonely!",
だるー、うるー、みたいな感じになっております。
a bit gloomy and teary.
はい、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Yes, please support it.
ふー、すげえ、汗をかいて…
Phew, amazing, I'm sweating...
おめでとう！かなた！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Kanata! Congratulations!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
サプライズ！サプライズできました！
Surprise! We came as a surprise!
え！？かなた、一人、一人で寂しくやってたから…
Eh!? Kanata, you were doing it alone, lonely, so...
一人でやらせませんよ！
We won't let you do it alone!
ゲストいないのでって、嘘！ちょっと、一人でやる気満々だったのに！
I said there are no guests, what, wait! I was fully prepared to do it alone!
ひどい、一人でやらせませんよ、一人じゃないよ、送るよ、送るよ
That's cruel, we won't let you do it alone, you're not alone, we'll send you off, send you off
あ、みんなが来てくれた！
Ah, everyone came!
来たー！
They came!
サプライズ！かなた、歌うまくなったね！
Surprise! Kanata, you've gotten so good at singing!
え！まじ！？やったー！ありがとう！
Eh! Really!? Yay! Thank you!
ちょっと我々から渡したいものがありますよね。
There's actually something we want to give you.
何何何何何マッジで？聞いてない知らない！
What, what, what? Seriously? I didn't hear about this!
マジで言ってない、マジで言ってない。
We seriously didn't tell you, seriously!
何すか？ヤダちょっと...
What is it? Oh no, wait...
泣かせないで。
Don't make me cry.
はい、どうぞー！
Here you go!
ありがとう！あ、すごい！
Thank you! Ah, amazing!
これ3人で選んだ花束です！
This is a bouquet we three picked out!
すごい！なんかとっても美しい、バラみたいな感じの...
Amazing! It looks like some really beautiful roses...
バーチャル空間には映らないんだけど...
It doesn't show up in virtual space, but...
僕たちだけのものです、みんな。
It's just for us, everyone.
え、すごい、こんなにでかい花束もらったことない！
Wow, amazing, I've never received such a huge bouquet before!
じゃ、一旦回収しますね！
Okay, we'll take it back for now!
あ、ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you so much.
3人で寄せ書きもしてきました！
We also wrote a message card together!
ありがとう！え、こんなの今見たら泣いちゃう。
Thank you! Oh, if I look at this now, I'll cry.
じゃ、回収します！後でね！
Then we'll take it back! See you later!
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
いや待って本当にやだ、本当にやだ...
No, wait, I really don't want this... I really don't...
やめる？やめるのやめる？
Stop? Stop graduating?
ここで？ここで？
Right here? Right here?
ここでやめて大エンディングにすればいい。
Just stop here and make it a grand happy ending!
3人も背負ってくれるってことで、一緒に。
Meaning you three will carry me along, together.
そう、そうよ、そうそう！
Yes, exactly! Yes, yes!
初配信明日！初配信明日！
Debut stream tomorrow! Debut stream tomorrow!
切り替えていくか... いや、もうありがとうみんな。
We switching over...? No, thank you so much everyone.
嬉しい...
I'm so happy...
めちゃめちゃ頼んだの、会いに来たいって。
We pleaded so much to be allowed to come see you.
そう、もう一人でなんか勝手に色んなもの背負ってさ... 行くなんて許せない！
Yeah, going off and carrying everything by yourself... we can't forgive that!
頼れよもっと！周りを頼れ！
Depend on us more! Rely on those around you!
ありがとう... 本当にわがままを言って、今日駆け付けさせていただきました！
Thank you... Honestly, we came here today even though we were being selfish!
本当に、本当に、本当に... すごい。ありがとうね。
Seriously, seriously, seriously... amazing. Thank you.
最後まで見るからね！
We'll watch until the very end!
行っちゃうの？
Are you leaving?
行かない、お前が行くな！お前が行くんだよ！私たちが先に行くんだ。
We aren't leaving, don't you leave! You're the one on stage! We're just heading back off-stage.
ありがとう... 嬉しい。
Thank you... I'm so happy.
頑張ってね！最後まで！
Do your best! Until the end!
まだ泣かないよ、まだあるからね！
Don't cry yet, there's still more to come!
吐きそう、本当に... 頼むよ。
I feel like throwing up, seriously... rely on you guys.
ありがとうね、これからもずっと仲良くしてください。
Thank you, please continue to be good friends with me.
一生友達だからね！ずっとこれからも先も！
We are friends for life! Always, from here on out!
縁側で茶飲み明かそうね、おばあちゃんになっても。
Let's drink tea on the porch even when we become old grandmas.
大好きだよ！頑張ってね！
We love you! Do your best!
ありがとう、またね、またね！
Thank you, see you, see you!
今回みんなに説明した感じで、ゲストは今回は呼べないけど頑張るよって言ってたんですけど...
As I explained to everyone, I said I couldn't invite guests but would do my best, but...
ころさん、あずちゃん、ラミィが来てくれました。本当にありがとうございます。
Koro-san, Azu-chan, and Lamy came. Thank you so much.
それではここからオリジナル楽曲が続いていきます。
Now, a series of original songs will follow.
歌えるのは最後になってしまうんですが、だからこそたくさんの思い出を思い出しながら、心を込めて歌っていこうと思います。
This is the last time I'll be singing them, but that's exactly why I want to sing them with all my heart, remembering so many memories.
ちょっとびっくりした。本当に素晴らしい友達を持って幸せです。ホロライブに入ってよかった。ということでじゃあ、聞いてね！
I was a bit surprised. I'm so happy to have such wonderful friends. I'm glad I joined Hololive. So please listen to...
[曲：きゅーぴっと]
[Song: Cupid]
君にキューピッドです むがむちゅっちゅっちゅっ
For you, I'm Cupid, frantically kiss-kiss-kissing
きっと夢にでてくるっちゅっちゅっちゅっ
Surely I'll appear in your dreams, kiss-kiss-kiss
ちゅっちゅっちゅっ ちゅっちゅっちゅっ ちゅっちゅっちゅっ
Chu, chu, chu, chu, chu, chu, chu, chu, chu
きゅっと抱きしめて
Hold me tight
[曲：インキャララバイ]
[Song: In-Chara Lullaby]
急に鳴りだす着信音 ヤダヤダヤダヤダ
A ringtone suddenly going off, no, no, no, no!
知らない番号とボイス ヤダヤダヤダヤダ
Unknown numbers and voices, no, no, no, no!
誰かが乗ってるエレベーター ヤダヤダヤダヤダ
An elevator with someone else in it, no, no, no, no!
そう 我らこそ インの者
Yes, we are the introverts!
笑おう笑おう 責めて笑おう アハハうふふなるほどです
Let's laugh, let's laugh, at least laugh. Ahaha, ufufu, I see.
来ない来ない 変わりまくり 反省反省また反省だ
No one's coming, things keep changing. Regret, regret, regret again!
鏡見るすら目を逸らした
I even turned my eyes away from looking in the mirror.
明日は今日より人間になりたい、なりたい、なりたい、なりたい！
Tomorrow I want to be more human than today, I want to, I want to, I want to!
おやすみなさい
Good night.
[曲：DA・LI・LA]
[Song: DA・LI・LA]
今度のランデブーは 目の前のわたし ちっともターゲットじゃないのに
This next rendezvous, even though I'm right in front of you, I'm not the target at all...
はにかむだけじゃつまんない
Just being shy is boring,
でしょ？
right?
あなたに捧げるわ
I will dedicate to you
私の愛を遺す全て
all of my love, everything I have to give.
この手は私を守るただためあったのね
These hands existed just to protect myself, didn't they?
いつでも君と暮らすどんなさようならも希望を
Always living with you, finding hope in any farewell.
ラストはうんと飾らなきゃ
I have to dress up the end as much as possible.
錆びと痛いだっけ
Rust and pain, was it?
チョイと少しだけ
Just a tiny bit...
DA・LI・LA 頭もキレイ
DA・LI・LA, even my head is clean.
[十万億土]
[Song: Juumanyokudo]
最上 意地を抜け出し野原みんな暴れ
Exiting our pride at the highest level, running wild in the fields,
重ねドレス 畳む鉄砲
layering dresses, folding up guns.
天の采は投げられたのでしょう
The die must have been cast from heaven.
最期 最期までお友達
Friends until the very, very end.
呼び起こす覚悟に こちらへおいでよ
To the resolve we awaken, come over here.
鏡を覗き込むは誰
Who is that peering into the mirror?
恐れず僕と歌おう
Sing with me without fear.
パッパッパッパッパッパッパッパ保存
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
巡り巡るよ現に 覚悟を召そう
Spinning round and round in reality, let's summon our resolve.
そろそろ終わりにしないか
Isn't it about time to bring this to an end?
今ならば美しいほら...
Look, it would be beautiful if it were now.
あー
Ah...
君は今更戻れない
You cannot turn back anymore.
あー
Ah...
[別世界]
[Song: Another World]
愛してくれ 僕のことも
Love me, too,
どうか邪魔はしないでから
please do not get in my way.
遠い遠い別世界まで
All the way to a far, far off, other world.
それ触れ得ない
It remains untouchable.
パパ ママ 幕が上がる
Papa, Mama, the curtain rises.
ただまた会いたくて あなたにこの拍手を
Just wanting to meet again, I give this applause to you.
[Knock it out!]
[Song: Knock it out!]
無敵なアイ アイ アイ 会いたいな
Invincible eye, eye, eye, I want to meet you.
着飾れ ほら ヒール 綺麗に フル装備
Dress up, look, heels beautifully, fully equipped.
無い ない ない 意味ないな
No, no, no, there's no meaning.
私の称賛 壊してクライド...
My praise, break it and collide.
[おらくる]
[Song: Oracle]
安楽安楽妄想、ね、傷つけたりしないで
Easy, easy delusion, hey, don't hurt me.
こんなバグだらけの世界になっちゃって ごめんね保存
I'm sorry this world ended up so full of bugs.
大丈夫、安全圏にようこそ、曖昧な世界にこれ
It's okay, welcome to the safe zone, to this ambiguous world.
見捨てないから ずっと今日も
Because I won't abandon you, today or forever.
安楽安楽神様、敵なし法になれ
Easy, easy God, become an unrivaled law.
固定的な点になるまで 愛してあげるね
I'll love you until we become a fixed point.
どん底で見届けて、ボロボロに恋焦がして
Watch over me from the rock bottom, yearning in tatters,
忘れちゃうくらい、笑っちゃうくらい、ちゃんとアイ・アイ・アイ・ラブ・ユー
enough to forget, enough to laugh, I really love love love, I love you!
[Last-resort]
[Song: Last-resort]
まずは息を殺せ 音は立てるなよ 奴らに気付かれる前に
First, hold your breath and don't make a sound, before they notice you.
次、爪を研ぎ澄ませ その時を待て 全ては一瞬のために
Next, sharpen your claws and wait for the moment, all for one instant.
そして覚悟しろ 最後の時は おののくような自分に
And prepare yourself, when the final moment comes, for your trembling self.
世界を変える奇跡は今
The miracle that will change the world is now!
カリスマの前に アイドルの凶器
Before charisma, the idol's weapon.
全部ぶち抜いてよ ラスト・リゾート
Shoot through everything, Last-resort!
トリックも最後さ 壊滅の世界で
This is the final trick, in a ruined world.
死に物狂い 射し抜いて 信じきれないなら
Pierce through desperately, if you can't believe it...
刹那
An instant...
射ち抜け
Shoot through.
すべてを
Everything.
壊して 一瞬に懸けて 放て ラスト・リゾート
Break it! Stake it all on an instant and fire! Last-resort!
僕のすべてを込めて 放て ラスト・リゾート
With all of myself, fire! Last-resort!
あなたがくれた希望で
With the hope you gave me,
約束の羽で今
with the promised wings, now...
羽ばたくじゃあ ともにゆく
I must spread my wings, we will go together!
誓いの先へ
Beyond our vow.
壊れるまで 遠く遠く
Until we break, far, far away,
今の僕は片翼でいい
for now, a single wing is enough for me.
飛べるよ 信じて
I can fly, believe in me.
飛べるよ その先へ
I can fly, beyond that point.
飛べるよ
I can fly!
楽園
Paradise...
永遠の
Eternal...
楽園のそばで
by the side of paradise...
あー
Ah...
きっといつか
Surely, someday...
でも
but...
あー
Ah...
遥か彼方
Far, far away...
待って
wait for me...
世界で一番のアイドル
[Song: The Best Idol in the World]
ふと思い出して 出会った日のこと
Suddenly remembering the day we met...
手を取って 僕らの旅が始まった
we took hands and our journey began.
走って転んで 涙を流しても
Even if we run, fall, and shed tears...
気がつけば ほら 顔合わせて笑う
before we know it, look, we face each other and laugh.
喜ぶ声が響いて 夢があふれだすね
Joyful voices echo, and our dreams overflow!
君がいなきゃ だめなんだ
Without you, it's no good.
せーの！
One, two!
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルだから
Because now, I'm the happiest idol in the world...
世界で一番の笑顔をあげちゃう
I'll give you the best smile in the world!
僕を見つけてくれた 愛してくれたから
Because you found me and loved me...
まだまだ終わらない ちゃんとついてきて
it's not over yet, make sure to keep up with me!
きらめく夢保存
This sparkling dream...
肩叩いてゆく 背中を見送った
Patting my shoulder, I watched your back leave.
雨上がり 君の傘を返したら
Once the rain stopped, and I returned your umbrella...
手を引いて進もう 一緒にどこまでも
let's take hands and move forward, together, wherever we go!
気がつけば ほら また前を向ける
Before we know it, look, we can face forward again.
戯れ合う言葉の中にも 愛を感じています
Even within our playful banter, I can feel the love.
僕じゃなきゃ だめなんでしょ？
It has to be me, right?
でしょ！
Right!
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルだから
Because now, I'm the happiest idol in the world...
世界で一番のときめきをあげちゃう
I'll give you the greatest heartbeat in the world!
僕を支えてくれた 推してくれたから
Because you supported me and pushed for me...
まだまだ終わらない 隣にいてよ
it's not over yet, stay by my side!
自信なんかない 不安ばかりだった
I had no confidence, only anxieties.
「もうやめよう」って泣いた日もあった
There were days when I cried, saying "Let's stop already."
そんな時浮かんでくるの みんなの声が保存
In those times, what comes to mind is everyone's voices!
今までで一番あきらめたくないの
This is what I want to give up on the least of all...
ずっとなりたかった 最強のアイドル
the strongest idol that I've always wanted to be!
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルだから
Because now, I'm the happiest idol in the world...
世界で一番の「大好き」をあげちゃう
I'll give you the biggest "I love you" in the world!
些細な日常も もっと輝かせて
Make even our trivial daily lives shine brighter...
まだまだ終わらない ありふれた奇跡を
it's not over yet, this commonplace miracle...
君と結んでいく
I'll weave it together with you.
いくよー！
Here we go!
ハイハイ！
Yeah, yeah!
なぬっ!? ビシッ おりゃっ! パシッ
What!? Bam! Bam! Smash!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
My comedic retort is sharp today too, it's clear weather!
ボロ、ユー、ム、バキッ
Vol-ume, crash!
手にする全部 It’s mine! くれくれ
Everything I get my hands on, It's mine! Gimme gimme!
適度にがんばろっか (そっか？)
Should we try working hard moderately? (Is that so?)
そんなんだっていいけどさ
That's fine too, but...
必死にがんばろっか (そうだ！)
should we try working hard desperately? (Yeah!)
それが僕らしいよな
That's more like me, isn't it?
そんで貧乏っちいじゃねえんだわ！
And I'm not poor or anything!
とんでピンチじゃねえんだわ！
And I'm not in a pinch or anything!
うん！万事がバッチリイケてるに決まってる！
Yeah! Everything is absolutely perfect, I'm bound to be cool!
かなたちゃん！
Kanata-chan!
どどん！前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Ta-da! Moving forward is great! Make sure to welcome me!
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
高まれ！
Rise up!
開空創造！ちゃんと驚嘆して
Creating the sky! Make sure to be amazed!
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
興奮しよう！
Let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん
Because I say so!
本当にするんだもん
Because I'll make it happen!
現実超えろ未来 あー！
Exceed reality, future, ah!
弱点も平気
Weaknesses are fine,
スイッチでランチャー！
Launcher with a switch!
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
進むのじゃ 特者生存ワンダラダーって
Move forward, "survival of the special" is what they call Wonderlader
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
楽しもう！
Let's enjoy!
面白がれること探しだまへ おおばばばー
Search for things you can enjoy, and go!
返事聞かせてくれ
Let me hear your answer!
右 左 どこじゃない
It's not right or left,
突き抜けていっちょくせん！
Break through in a straight line!
つまりたくらんだら発射オーライだ！
In other words, once planned, it's launch alright!
ワクワクせん？ しょ！
Aren't you excited? Let's go!
聞いて！みんなと離れるのが寂しいのとか
Listen! The sadness of being apart from everyone,
ガッキーの結婚が立ち直ってません！
And I still haven't recovered from Gakky's marriage!
僕をアイドルにしてくれて、みんな本当にありがとう！
Thank you all so much for making me an idol!
なんだよそんなこと言っちゃダメだ、おバカ！
What's that? Don't say such things, you dummy!
わあ、すごい！ありがとう！
Wow, amazing! Thank you!
ピンチもチャンスで全部お構いなし
Pinch or chance, I don't care at all
虎視眈々と生いたいんだもんだって
Because I want to live vigilantly like a tiger
いきごごごいいんだもんで
My spirits are at fifty-five percent, you know!
全方位にガッツリ合わせてハイ！タッチ！
Matching perfectly in all directions, High Touch!
いっつも心はちゃんと充填で
My heart is always fully charged,
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
いっパいの好奇心 まさに一心で
Full of curiosity, with one heart,
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
いっさいがっさいって
All of it,
言い聞かせるんだ
I'll tell myself.
調子に乗ったらすぐ飽きられちゃうから あー！
If I get carried away, people will get tired of me quickly, ah!
対当なロボット どどんと捨てて
Dumping the equivalent robot with a bang
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
進むのじゃ 特者生存ワンダラダーって
Move forward, "survival of the special" is what they call Wonderlader
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
仕込み付け
Train and prepare,
努力とは最後まで諦めないこと
Effort means not giving up until the very end!
メモっておいて
Take a note of that!
本当はベイビー 自信がないよ
Honestly, baby, I have no confidence,
本当はベイビー 不安ばかりで泣きそうだって
Honestly, baby, I'm so anxious I could cry.
ごめんねベイビー 挫けないって決めたの
I'm sorry, baby, but I've decided not to give up!
だからベイビー 挑戦したいよ
So baby, I want to take on the challenge,
未開の地 無限のフィールドへ！
To unexplored lands, to an infinite field!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Moving forward is great! Make sure to welcome me!
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
高まれ！
Rise up!
開空創造！ちゃんと驚嘆して
Creating the sky! Make sure to be amazed!
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
興奮しよう！
Let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん
Because I say so!
本当にするんだもん
Because I'll make it happen!
現実超えろ未来 あー！
Exceed reality, future, ah!
弱点も平気
Weaknesses are fine,
スイッチでランチャー！
Launcher with a switch!
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
進むのじゃ 特者生存ワンダラダーって
Move forward, "survival of the special" is what they call Wonderlader
（ワンダラダーラ）
(Wonder-la-der-la)
楽しもう！
Let's enjoy!
面白がれること探し放題です
You can look for things to enjoy as much as you want!
無限のフィールドね
It's an infinite field,
ラーニングしなくてもいい
You don't even have to learn!
ど真ん中いっちょくせん！
Straight through the very center!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In other words, this is my answer!
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を
Stand tall! The meaning of living in the present,
明くる日も 明くる日も確かめて進め！
Confirm it day after day, and move forward!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はぁ、みんな、
Phew, everyone...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
はい、えー聞いていただいたのはオリ曲メドレー、
Yes, so what you just heard was an original song medley.
メドレーにしました。繋ぎましたよ！
I made it a medley. I stitched them together!
そして『世界で一番のアイドル』作詞をしました。
And I wrote the lyrics for "The World's Number One Idol".
この時、卒業だって考えてなかったから
At that time, I wasn't even thinking about graduation,
本当に、あの、いっぱい聴いてほしい曲です。
so it's a song I really want you to listen to a lot.
そして『特者生存ワンダラダー!!』でした！はい！
And that was "Tokusha Seizon Wanderlader!!"! Yes!
これを初めてね、出しましたね、オリジナル曲ですけれども。
That was the first time I've performed it, it's my original song.
ちょっと語りたいこといっぱいあるんですけど、やっぱりあの服だよね？
There's a lot of things I want to talk about, but first, it's gotta be that outfit, right?
ってことで、一秒着替えしてきます。
So, I'm going to do a one-second outfit change!
はい！
Ta-da!
やっぱりこれだよね、みんな！はい、こんかなた！
It's gotta be this, everyone! Hello, Kon-Kanata!
キャッチコピーは、握力50キロ、ぎゅーぎゅー握りつぶしちゃうぞ！ホロライブ4期生、かなたちゃんこと天音かなたです！
My catchphrase is: with 50kg grip strength, I'll squeeze you tight! Hololive 4th gen, Kanata-chan also known as Amane Kanata!
はい、ということでね、録音、あぶなっ！
Alright, with that said... wait, recording? That was close!
危ない橋は渡らないようにしておきまして、
I'll make sure not to cross any dangerous bridges,
このような感じでいきたいと思うんですけれども、
and proceed with this kind of vibe.
って、みんながね、たくさん聴いてくれたおかげと言いますか、本当にありがとうございました...
It's all thanks to everyone listening to it so much... Thank you so very much...
と思っています。
That's how I feel.
えー、みんなね、あの...
Also, everyone...
このあとですね、あの、22時20分から、最後の「歌ってみた」...
After this, at 22:20, my last cover song video...
みんなと約束してました、あの、動画消えちゃって歌い直そうって言っていた、あの、「KING」を投稿するので絶対見てくださいね！
I'm posting "KING," which I promised to re-record after the video got deleted, so please make sure to watch it!
ふぅ...
Whew...
毎日は一緒にいてくれたへい民、ホロライブの大好きなメンバーたち、そしてたくさん支えてくださった、本当にお世話になった方々全ての方に感謝しています。
I'm grateful to the Heimin who were with me every day, my beloved Hololive members, and everyone who supported and took care of me.
夢のような時間を本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for this dream-like time!
こころこ...ここで噛むのね。子供の頃の「アイドルになりたい」という夢が、作詞作曲をしてみたいという夢を、叶いました。
My hea... I had to stumble here. My childhood dream of becoming an idol and my dream of writing and composing songs have come true.
そして、最後の曲ですが、まだ歌うんですよ。
And now for the final song, but I'm still going to sing.
僕が初めて作詞作曲した楽曲があります。
There is a song that I wrote and composed for the first time.
今はいない同期、ココの卒業に合わせて、4期生のトワ、ルーナ、わために捧げた楽曲です。
To mark the graduation of our generation-mate Coco, who is no longer here, I dedicated this song to 4th generation's Towa, Luna, and Watame.
前を向いて笑顔で、この楽曲で活動を最後にしたいと思います。
I would like to bring my activities to a close with this song, looking forward with a smile.
それでは聴いてください。「キセキ結び」！
Now, please listen to: "Kiseki Musubi"!
キセキ結び
[Song: Kiseki Musubi]
約束しようよ 僕ら出会えた奇跡
Let's make a promise, so we won't forget the miracle of our meeting.
忘れないように
So that we never forget.
夢抱いて集う 青春アニメみたいに
Gathering with dreams, like in a youth anime,
HAPPYなエンドになる 彼方へ飛ぶよ
it'll be a happy ending. I will fly towards the distance.
寝ぼけ眼アクビして 今日は何をしようか
Yawning with sleepy eyes, what should we do today?
永遠に続く海を 駆け抜ける
Running through the endless sea...
今はため息よりも 勇気を
Now, courage rather than sighs.
諦めるなんてないの
There's no such thing as giving up.
ここで歌う僕の声は聞こえてますか？
Can you hear my voice singing here?
君に届け
May it reach you.
学校の友達じゃ きっとなかった出会いだった
It was an encounter we surely wouldn't have had if we were just school friends.
何年も先の 遥か遠くまで
To the far distance, years ahead,
ささくれた言葉も 誰かの笑顔になる
even splintered words can bring a smile to someone.
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡
With our own colors, the miracle of tying stars,
キラキラ輝く ステージに連れてくよ
I'll take you to the glittering stage.
泣いて笑ってはしゃいで 毎日がジェットコースター
Crying, laughing, having fun, every day is a roller coaster.
たまにはね 寝転んで お昼寝しよう
Sometimes, let's just lie down and take a nap.
ちょっと自信ないとき こっそり泣いてリセットして
When I lack confidence, I'll secretly cry and reset.
今日だけは泣いちゃうこと 許してね
Please forgive me for crying just for today.
未来の僕が アルバム開く
My future self opens the album.
傷ついた写真だって 宝物だ
Even the hurt pictures are treasures.
僕の愛は見えていますか？
Can you see my love?
君に届け
May it reach you.
過去も個性も 性格も違うけれど
Though our pasts, personalities, and characters are different,
夜明けが来るときは 瞼ぎゅっと瞑り
when dawn comes, close your eyes tight.
もう1回 もう1回 絶対に諦めない
One more time, one more time, I will never give up.
前を向く背中を追う 下手くそな僕でも
Even if I'm clumsy at chasing the back of someone looking forward,
君の隣にいたくて 走るよ
I run because I want to be by your side.
誰にも言えずに 描いた夢が
The dream I painted without telling anyone,
たとえ叶わないとしても
even if it doesn't come true,
ボロボロの靴でも カッコよくなくても ああ
even with worn-out shoes, even if it's not cool, ah...
おそろい あの日の僕ならなんて言う
All together, what would my self from that day say?
「止まらないで」
“Don't stop”
初めて僕らが出会った日
The day we met for the first time,
まるで昨日のことみたいに思い出すけど
I can remember it like it was yesterday, but...
もう行こうか 最後に今
Shall we go now? At last, now,
重なるキセキ
over-lapping miracles.
僕らの声を 聞いて ずっと ずっと
Listen to our voices, forever and ever.
嬉しい日　楽しい日　悲しい日は枯れぬ希望
On happy days, fun days, and on sad days, unwithering hope
それぞれの色で
With each of our own colors
星結ぶ奇跡
A miracle that ties the stars together
キラキラ輝くステージで
On this shining, sparkling stage,
約束
Let's make...
しよう
...a promise
いつかここで
Someday, right here,
また会おう
let's meet again.
バイバイ！ありがとう！
Bye-bye! Thank you!
ホロライブ4期生、アイドルの天音かなたでした！
I was Hololive's 4th generation idol, Amane Kanata!
6年間、本当に幸せな日々でした。
These 6 years were truly happy days.
へいみん、不器用な僕を応援してくれて、ありがとう。
Heimin, thank you for supporting clumsy me.
ずっとずっと、大好きだよ。
I will always, always love you.
ずっとずっと、宝物だよ！
You will always, always be my treasure!
みんな本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much, everyone!
ありがとう...
Thank you...